Guide to the English Documents Collection, 1552-1875
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES VII. MISCELLANEOUS
  - Devon
    - Terms of a survey on behalf of Richard Berryman for letting land to farm Trillacot, North Petherwin, Devon, 27 January 1802; (7.5" x 12") (Folder 2.09)
    - Court Citation to Mrs. Frances (Fanny) Pellatt, regarding the estate of her late husband, Henry Pellatt, Canterbury, 20 September 1803; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.10)
    - Check for wages for John Teague who served in the Navy aboard the Prince and the Trent, and died 1798. Check issued to his sister Letitia Teague, Plymouth, Devon, 14 May 1803; (10.5" x 17.5") (Folder 6.10)
    - Shares in the the Little Duke Copper Mine in Tavistock, Devon, July 1806; (2 certificates, 8.5" x 12") (Folder 6.12)
    - Affidavits regarding the July 1816 fire in Buckfastleigh, Devon, May 1817; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.16)
    - Affidavit of Reverend Matthew Lowndes regarding the July 1816 fire in Buckfastleigh, Devon, 16 June 1817; (8.5" x 13.5") (Folder 2.17)
    - Return of people liable for militia service, including 63 names, ages and occupations, Bardninch, Devon, 1817; (15" x 19.5") (Folder 14.11)
    - Pedigree of the Turner Family of Cadbury, Devon, 24 February 1819; (8" x 12.5") (Folder 2.18)
    - Chancery Court document regarding a survey of an estate in Cadbury, Devon, possibly owned by John Pitt, June 1819; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.19)
    - Letter to William Drew, Esq., London, from someone whose mother has just died in Exeter, 16 February 1822; (7.5" x 9") (Folder 2.28)
    - Document regarding tolls and repairs for the roads from Tavistock to Morwellham, Devon, 14 December 1822; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.27)
    - List of deeds held by Robert Talley, [Devon?], 8 February 1823; (7.5" x 9") (Folder 2.29)
    - List of materials, dated 1651-1776, received by the executors of the estate of Ann Kirkham, Washbourne, Harberton, Devon, 2 December 1825; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.30)
    - Rental records of the Manor of Meldon, Devon, for one year, 1833; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.32)
    - Printed appeal from the Court of Chancery re will of George Acland Barbor, Fremington, Devon, 1842; (11" x 17.5") (Folder 6.21)
    - List of pieces performed at the Theatre Royal Devonport between September 1844 and February 1845, addressed to the Dramatic Authors Society, 2 July 1845; (8.5" x 10") (Folder 2.38)
    - Stock certificates from the Cawson Hill Copper, Lead and Tin Mining Company, Devon, owned by Matthew Johnston, 12 November 1852; (4 certificates, 9" x 9.5") (Folder 6.22)
    - Letter by James Thomson, architect and surveyor, describing the West Hoe Estate at Plymouth as a potential building site, ca. 1850s; (8" x 10") (Folder 2.48)
    - Letter from Reverend Owen Lucas O'Neil, Cornworthy Vicarage, Totnes, Devon, 4 July 1864; (5.5" x 8") (Folder 2.41)
    - Letter from "Dippertown Office" regarding land at Lewtrenchard belonging to Parson Gould, 6 August 1865; (7" x 9") (Folder 2.42)
    - Receipt, Colyton, Devon, 23 July [18??]; (4" x 6") (Folder 2.47)
  - Kent
    - Receipt, payment for house in Deptford, Kent, 20 November 1651; (8" x 12") (Folder 1.01)
    - Agreement between [Clement Tipp?] and John Kingsford of Canterbury, 28 January 1675; (8" x 12") (Folder 1.04)
    - "Mortgage agreement of William Barnes, Boughton, Kent", 9 October 1688; (7" x 10.5") (Folder 1.06)
    - Agreement between John Lemott Honywood of Marks Hall, Essex and John [Hunt?] of Kent, 22 May 1689; (7" x 9") (Folder 1.07)
    - Letter to John Mascall, New Romney, from [John Brewer?], ca. 1680s; (6" x 7.5") (Folder 2.45)
    - Agreement about land or a mortgage by Charles [Lunkin?], Kent, 26 June 1701; (8" x 12") (Folder 1.11)
    - William Courthope of Paternoster Row, London, about a mortgage due to him from tenants in Cranbrook, Kent, 8 October 1718; (8" x 12") (Folder 1.16)
    - Articles of Agreement between John [Sharpsigh?], Stephen [Sharpsigh?], and George Courthope about land in Cranbrook, Kent, 12 February 1721; (7.5" x 12") (Folder 1.17)
    - Request for reparations regarding the lease of the Kingshead Inn, Dartford, Kent, formerly owned by Anno Rooves, 3 November 1726; (8" x 13") (Folder 1.20)
    - Articles of agreement between John Garnett Stevens of Chislehurst, Kent, and Benjamin Osgood "citizen and Carpenter of London" regarding a lease, 24 April 1726; (8" x 13") (Folder 1.21)
    - Draft of a verdict against Thomas Bridges of Maidstone, Kent, for sinking his boat in the Medway River, blocking river traffic, ca. 1753; (10" x 16") (Folder 5.16)
    - Decl. by Thomas Babb, appointing wife Charlotte to act – relates to Barnstaple group, 14 September 1793; (10" x 16") (Folder 6.07)
    - Documentation that Elizabeth (Boorsman) Middleton received five pounds from the estate of Thomas Ballard of High Halden, Kent, 15 January 1794; (8" x 12") (Folder 1.22)
    - Copy of 1746 fine for William Farrant, etc. sent to William Walter, Solicitor, Kent, 10 September 1801; (8" x 10") (Folder 2.08)
    - Final agreement between the families of Samuel Reader and William price regarding property in Cranbrook, Hawkhurst, Frittendon, Tenterden, and Brookland, Kent, Easter 1804; (13" x 16.5") (Folder 6.11)
    - Agreement between William Scott and John Bently for Bently to rent the "Castle Quay," from Scott, Barnstaple Quay, 24 June 1820; (8" x 9.5") (Folder 2.20)
    - Request to the County of Kent Sheriff to appear before the Commission of Sewers, Kent, 1 June 1820; (8" x 12.5") (Folder 2.21)
    - Agreement between Stephen Bates and Henry Woodgate regarding the lease of a farm at either Seven Oaks or Cranbrook, Kent, 8 October 1821; (7.5" x 9") (Folder 2.24)
    - Agreement to settle the debt between George and John Pearce of Hoo, Kent, and Henry Dance of Lincoln’s Inn Fields, Middlesex in order to release Dance from the King's Bench Prison under the Insolvent Debtors Act, 20 May 1822; (10" x 15.5") (Folder 6.15)
    - List of Court of Assize jurors, Kent, 1822; (6.5" x 16.5") (Folder 6.14)
    - List of Court of Assize jurors, Kent, 1822; (8.5" x 13") (Folder 2.26)
    - List of debtors discharged or removed from the jail at Maidstone, Kent, during the tenure of Sir John Shelly Sidney (Baronet) as Sherriff, ca. 1822; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.23)
    - Bill of sale for the Wye, a schooner purchased by William Scott and other shareholders from John Scott the Elder, certified by the Custom House, Bristol, 21 October 1829; (16.5" x 22") (Folder 14.14)
    - Letter from H. Drake regarding the bankruptcy of William Scott and his lease of a quay in Barnstaple to John Bentley, 25 July 1830; (8" x 10") (Folder 2.31)
    - Assignment of shares in ship, Wye of Bristol, after bankruptcy of William Scott, 1830; (23" x 30") (Folder M.22)
    - Genealogical excerpt from the Fitzgerald Family Bible relating to the settling of the estate of George Fitzgerald, surgeon of Deal, Kent, 30 November 1837; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.33)
    - Order of Sale of the Poor House in Sevenoaks, Kent in accordance with the Poor Law Amendment Act 1834, 16 Nov 1838; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.34)
    - Stock certificate from the Gwendraeth Anthracite and Iron Company, owned by Sarah Mackie, Westernham, Kent, 15 Jan 1839; (10" x 15") (Folder 6.19)
    - Memorandum of agreement regarding the Rochester Bridge Act of 1846, made betweeen John Gibbs of Strood and Michael Smith Comport of High Halstow, Kent, 7 September 1848; (8" x 13") (Folder 2.40)
  - Somerset
    - I.P.M., death of John Selwode, Som., 21 September 1601; (10.5" x 12") (Folder 4.01)
    - Obligation / Indenture of Thomas Brooks, Bedminster, Bristol [formerly Somerset], 4 June 1665; (7.5" x 14") (Folder 1.03)
    - Obligation / Indenture of Thomas Brooks, Bedminster, Bristol [formerly Somerset], 1668; (10" x 12") (Folder 4.06)
  - Unidentified and Miscellaneous
    - "Compotus Manerii de Elloughe etc." — Book of accounts for the Manors of Sotterly, Ugghal, and Willingham, all in Suffolk, 1552-1599; (1 volume) (Box 15)
    - Court document relating to Thomas Perrivall, 1654?; (11.5" x 22") (Folder 7.02)
    - Agreement, Charles Elstop to William East – lands to be sold, location unstated, 1694; (13" x 16.5") (Folder 4.15)
    - Witness to exec. Of deeds of L & R by Richard Hart of Plymouth, butcher to James Keating, sugar-baker of P., of 2 tens in Trevile St., all. Butchers Lane, Plymouth, 17 August 1722; (7" x 12") (Folder 1.19)
    - Document regarding the debts of the late husband of Mary Cullymore, [Plymouth?], 24 September 1735; (8" x 12.5") (Folder 1.27)
    - Receipt for a cow, a heifer, and a calf sold by Robert Grean, 5 September 1772; (4" x 5.5") (Folder 1.33)
    - Sale of a building from Robert Grean to John Mitchell, Higate Hill, East Grinstead, 29 September 1772; (5.5" x 6") (Folder 1.34)
    - Correspondence to and from Reverend William Wilson concerning the marriage of Thomas Todd and Elizabeth Wooler and her inheritance from the estate of her uncle, John Wooler, Wolsingham, Durham, 1791-1797; (9 letters) (Folder 1.39)
    - Inventory of Captain Pannell’s Goods in his house at Blackheath, ca. 1800; (10" x 15") (Folder 6.09)
    - Westminster, Middx, Insurance policy, 1815; (19" x 23.5") (Folder 14.10)
    - Design for Little Gaddesden gate, Ashridge Park, Hertfordshire, 21 November 1821; (8" x 12.5") (Folder 2.25)
    - Copy Woolmers Exeter & Plymouth Gazette, 18 July 1829; (16" x 21") (Folder 14.13)
    - Agreement between Ann Bickell and the adventurers of Wheal Friendship mine for the sale of a house in Blackdown, Mary Tavy, Devon, 23 January 1839; (8" x 10") (Folder 2.36)
    - Printed appeal from the Court of Chancery re will of Sir John Trevelyan - re Manor of Seaton, 1841; (11.5" x 17.5") (Folder 6.20)
    - 2 pages (83-84) from E. H. W. Dunkin's "Contributions Towards the Ecclesiastical History of the Deanery of South Malling in the County of Sussex," Sussex Archaeological Collections Relating to the History and Antiquities of the County, Vol 26, 1875; (6" x 9") (Folder 2.01)
    - 2 pages (465-466) from an unidentified book including information about the Ashendon Hundred, (9" x 12") (Folder 4.25)